serenahotels.com 2017-11-10

# 

## Privacy statement

**The protection of your privacy is very important to us**

The privacy and security of your personal information is very important to us. We do not share your personal information in ways not disclosed in our privacy policy or without your informed permission. We value your trust very highly, and we strive to protect the confidentiality and appropriate use of any personal information you provide to us.

**The kind of personal information we may collect from you**

We will only collect such personal information as you knowingly and voluntarily divulge to us during your use of our website. Such information will allow us to process your hotel booking and will include such things as your name, telephone number, date of birth, residential or business address, email address, age range and gender. The collection of such information will allow us to protect your confidentiality by verifying your identity. It is our intention that this policy will protect your personal information from being dealt with in any way that is inconsistent with applicable local privacy laws.  
Following a stay in one of our hotels, your hotel stay information will also be collected and stored by our hotels locally, and subsequently transferred to a centralized database. This facilitates aggregated trend analysis used for hotel management purposes such as planning new hotel locations, evaluating hotel amenities, guest preferences, and advertisement planning. In addition, your business with us is valued and we may use the record of your stay to send you via postal mail or email, communications such as guest surveys or promotional offers and benefits. You may “opt-out” or choose to be excluded from these communications by contacting our customer service department.

**Information collection in relation to children**

Our web site does not intentionally solicit or collect personal information about children under the age of 13. If you are under 13 and would like to use our web site, please ask a parent or guardian for assistance.  
**How do we collect your personal information?**

When you place a hotel reservation, we request your name, email address, mailing address, phone number, credit card number and expiration date. We use this information to process and fulfill your reservation. Additional optional information in your profile is collected for specific services such as check-in conveniences or room preferences. This data is stored in data bases protected from intrusion and unauthorized viewing by commercially available software products we purchase in good faith from third party suppliers, and you do not have to re-enter it with each visit to our web site. It is also used to recognize you as a repeat customer so that we may offer you additional benefits. We may also collect personal information when you sign up for a Serena special offer or promotion, or when you complete the details requested in the ‘contact us’ box.

We also collect certain technical information from your computer each time you request a page during a visit to our web sites. This information may include your Internet Protocol (IP) address, your computer's operating system, browser type and the address of a referring Web site, if any. We collect this information to enhance the quality of your experience during your visit to our site and will not sell or rent this information to any third parties. We also use various web site analytics tools and technologies regarding activities on our web site that require storage of web session data. The overall aim of these tools is to aid in making the website easy to use and to proactively identify and correct error conditions. These tools and technologies are also used to assist web site visitors who report problems in the use of our website. Stored web session data is never sold or rented to third parties and is purged when these purposes have been fulfilled.

Should you apply for employment with the Serena Group of Hotels by submitting an application and/or resume on-line, specific information will be collected but will ONLY be used only for the purposes of considering your application for the posted position.

**How we use your personal information**  
Information we collect on our web sites may be used to enhance your experience in the following ways:  

To confirm your hotel reservations

To request your evaluation of your stay with us

To send you emails that relate to your stay with us

To process credit card payments. _Kindly note for online payment refunds via creditdebit cards, these will be effected less transactional fee charges._

To respond to your customer-service enquiries or requests

To communicate special offers and featured items to you.

Note: you can decline to accept such email correspondence at any time: simply contact: [ecommerce@serena.co.ke](mailto:ecommerce@serena.co.ke) .

**When and with whom we share your personal information**  
We ONLY share your personal customer information with the hotels within our group, our travel representatives and our trusted service providers and contractors. Such sharing will ONLY be in the interests of fulfilling customer reservations; offering certain products and services in connection with our web site; communicating to customers via email; providing customer service; enhancing and improving customers' online experience; enabling access to our partners' sites; providing a personalized online experience; and completing credit card transactions. We also guarantee that all such third parties have agreed to comply with our privacy policies.  
Aside from the purposes described above, **we do not share your personal information with any other third parties** unless we have your permission or under special circumstances, such as when we believe in good faith that the disclosure is required by law or to protect the safety of hotel guests, employees, the public or our property. We do, however, reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order or legal process served on our business entity. We may also share aggregated demographic and statistical information in the course of our business with certain third parties. This sharing does not include any personal information that can identify any individual person.  
**Links to other sites**  
Please note that our site may offer links to other sites, and that the privacy policies of these sites may differ from our own. We advise you to check the privacy policies of other Web sites before disclosing any personal information, we cannot accept responsibility for the conduct of companies linked to our website. In any event, please note that these sites do not share your personal information with us.  
**How we protect the security of your personal information**  
We strive to ensure the security, integrity and privacy of personal information submitted to our sites, and we review and update our security measures in light of current technologies. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be totally secure.

However, we will endeavour to take all reasonable steps to protect the personal information you may transmit to us. Once we do receive your transmission, we will also make our best efforts to ensure its security on our systems.

In addition, our employees and the contractors who provide services related to our information systems are obliged to respect the confidentiality of any personal information held by us. However, we will not be held responsible for events arising from unauthorised access to your personal information.   
**Email communications  
**If you choose to receive periodic communications from us, we may from time to time send you email messages describing new promotions, featured hotels and special offers. You can choose to stop receiving these emails at any time by using the "Unsubscribe" feature included on each email message.  
**Right of access to data.**

You have a right of access to your data by sending a written request to:

Customer Service  
Serena Hotels  
P.O. Box 48690,  
Nairobi, Kenya   
Email: dataprotection@serenahotels.com

**Changes to our Privacy Policy**  
We reserve the right to change, modify or amend this policy at any time. However, if there are changes made to the use of users' personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify you by posting a notice on our Web site for 30 days.

**Problems and Questions**

If we become aware of any ongoing concerns or problems with our web sites, we will take these issues seriously and work to address these concerns. If you have any further queries relating to our Privacy Policy, or you have a problem or complaint, please contact us.
